警察学校5
迈阿密之旅
下面有人
There's somebody down there.
他走了没? 走了没?
Is he gone yet? Is he gone?
- 长官 他走了 - 好 我们走
- Sir, he's gone. - Okay, let's go.
有人在吗?
Anybody home?
白痴
Idiot.
关门
Close the door.
- 你知道要搜查什么吧? - 是 不! 电灯开关?
- You know what to look for, right? - Yeah. No. A light switch?
拜托你不要像个白痴
Please try not to be such an idiot.
- 我没事 - 没人问你?
- I'm okay. - Nobody asked.
- 他不在这里 - 谁?
- He's not here. - Who?
- 赫斯局长 - 他当然不在这里
- Commissioner Hurst. - Of course he's not here.
问题是 现在时间是凌晨三点
It's 3:00 in the morning. That's the point.
或许我们应先打个电话来?
Maybe we should have called first.
如果我查这些文件的时候让局长看着我的话
If I'd wanted the Commissionerto watch me while I looked at his files...
我可以和他约好 白天来这里拜访
I could have come in during the dayand made an appointment.
等等 你是说 我们闯进来是违法的
Wait a minute. You meanwe're breaking and entering illegally?
- 我们正在犯法 - 不!
- We are breaking the Law? - No.
我们没有犯法
We are not breaking the Law.
我们只是行为不走寻常路
We are merely stretching it a little.
犯法无所谓 只要你理由恰当
It's okay to break the lawif you have a good reason...
- 就像是你妈妈或者是医生的便条一样 - 我们没犯法
- like a note from your doctor or mom. - We are not breaking the Law.
只是不走寻常路
We are stretching it.
你明白吗?
Do you get it?
- 不明白 长官 - 我口袋里有注解 可以吗?
- Not really, sir. - I got a note in my pocket, okay?
可以 你为何不早说?
Okay. Why didn't you just say that?
赫斯局长
Commissioner Hurst....
艾里克.拉萨德校长
"Comdt. Eric Lassard."
这就是了
Well, there he is.
多年来 你占着警官学院校长的职位
For years you've kept mefrom my rightful place...
直压着我
as Commandant of the Police Academy.
你一直处心积虑地往上爬 对不
You always manage to come out on topsomehow, don't you?
我知道这案件里藏有玄机
I know that there issomething in this file...
可以助我晋升
that is going to help meget the upper hand for a change.
谁在里面?
Who's in there?
赫斯局长?
Commissioner Hurst?
我是 谁在外面?
Yes. Who's out there?
管理员巴伯
Bob the janitor, sir.
我明白 长官 今晚我没看见你
I understand, sir.And I didn't see you here tonight.
- 很感激你 巴伯 - 非常感激 巴伯
- I really appreciate that, Bob. - Yeah. Thanks a lot, Bob.
- 普卡特? - 是 长官
- Proctor. - Yes, sir?
就是它 根据此项记录 艾里克.拉萨德校长
This is it! According to these records,Comdt. Eric Lassard...
去年就已达退休年龄
reached the state'smandatory retirement age Last year!
- 普卡特 你不明白这意义吗? - 不!
- Don't you see what this means? - No!
普卡特
Proctor.
它表示拉萨德校长
This means that Comdt. Lassard...
年前就该退休 辞去校长职位
should have retiredfrom the Police Academy a year ago.
然而 这份资料被疏忽了
Somehow, this informationjust slipped through.
我觉得分为一个正直警察的责任
I find it my dutyas a conscientious police officer...
便是把这案件送交人事部
to see to itthat this file reaches the Personnel Office.
我们还要闯进那里去吗?
Are we going to have tobreak in there, too, sir?
凯瑟琳.佩奇警官
Officer Katherine Page.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, sir.
卡拉.格兰特警官
Officer Carla Grant.
谢谢
Thank you.
比尔.贝克警官
Officer Bill Baker.
谢谢! 长官
Thank you, sir.
班比.布连顿警官
Officer Bambi Brandon.
- 谢谢 长官 - 谢谢
- Thank you, sir. - Thank you.
凯文.威尔森警官
Officer Kevin Wilson.
最后一位 当然 不是排名最末
And last, but certainly not least,not in any way...
绝对不是 汤马斯.康可林警官
Officer Thomas Conklin.
又名房屋
Also known as House.
恭喜你们
Congratulations!
我会怀念你们 第 88年班
I'll miss you, Class of '88.
漂亮
Nice.
我经历了许多届学生的入校毕业
I've seen a lot of graduating classes.
我想说这期属于最优秀的行列
And let me say thatthis is one of the very best of them.
我们都清楚拉萨德校长优异的表现
Clearly, Comdt. Lassardhas outdone himself this time.
我在这荣幸地宣布 艾里克.拉萨德校长
It's my privilege to announcethat Comdt. Eric Lassard...
将在今年迈阿密海滩举行的
will be honoredas Police Officer of the Decade...
全国警官大会中
at this year'sNational Police Chiefs Convention...
荣获"十年度最佳警察"
to be held in Miami Beach.
拉萨德校长
This Academy owes a great debt...
对本校作出了巨大贡献
to the vision of Comdt. Lassard...
使我接下来想说的很难说出
which makes what I have to say nexteven more difficult.
很令人感伤 令人遗憾地
It is with great sadness and regret...
我必须宣告
that I must announceEric Lassard's retirement...
拉萨德校长的退休
as Commandant of this police academy.
拉萨德校长已达退休年龄
Comdt. Lassard has reachedthis state's mandatory retirement age.
我们将选择一位有能力的继任者
A gualified successor will,of course, be chosen.
但是新校长的工作是很不容易的
But the new commandantwill have no easy task filling these shoes.
- 我们该怎么办? - 住口!
- What are we going to do? - Kick some butt.
- 这是不对的 - 太不公平
- It's just not right. - This is so unfair.
- 我从来没看到他这样子 - 他一直都很坚强
- I've never seen him like this. - He was always so strong.
- 警校一直是他的支柱 - 现在 他失去了
- The Academy was his strength. - Now he's lost it.
这样坐不对
It's just not right.
- 我们为何不杀了某人 - 校长
- Why don't we just shoot somebody? - Commandant.
- 不 不值得 - 恭喜光荣退休
- No. He ain't worth it. - Congratulations on your retirement!
对不起 我是说 恭喜您在迈阿密获奖
I'm sorry, I mean on your awardin Miami Beach.
对于您的退休 长官
Concerning your retirement, sir...
我只想说跟您在一起工作是多么舒适
I want you to know how much I've enjoyedworking with you all these years...
我也希望你能在
and how much I hope you enjoy...
您早已该进行退休期好好休养
your long overdue rest.
我想我该去读书了
Well, I guess I'll run alongand read my book.
大家保持联络
Keep in touch, everyone.
他们一直大眼瞪小眼的我们得想想办法
They just keep staring at each other.We've got to do something.
我知道你的感受 长官 我也曾经想从塔上跳下
I know how you feel, sir.I was ready to toss in the towel, too.
但我遇到了改变我生命的人 那个人就是你 长官
Then I met a man who changed my life.That man was you, sir.
他说 做你所该做的 即使是卑微的
He said, "Take what you have,however little...
也要尽力做好它
"and do your best with it."
不妥协 不失望 那才是我们所认识的拉萨德
"Never quit. Never lose hope."That's the lassard I knew.
现在 那个拉萨德到那儿去了?
And where is that lassard now?
就在这里
Right here.
天哪 你们是对的
By God, you're right.
我真为自己感到可耻 再也不会了!
I was feeling sorry for myself. No more.
在迈阿密海滩全国警官大会中
I'm still being honored...
我还是会获奖
at the National Police Chiefs Conventionin Miami Beach.
- 绝对是 长官 - 我要昂首挺胸去参加
- Affirmative, sir! - Go there with my head held high.
- 是的! 长官 - 那将是我最光荣的一刻
- Yes, sir! - It will be my finest hour!
- 鸭子! - 蹲下
- Duck! - Get down!
就是这精神 长官
That's the spirit, sir.
真准
Good shot.
如果我忠诚的学生到那里跟我一起分享荣誉
It would make my crowning momentonly greater...
我的受奖仪式将会更加有意父
if my loyal graduates could be thereto share it with me.
迈阿密海滩? 那些风浪板 阳光 欢乐
Miami Beach? All that surf, sun, and fun?
你们可以见见我的侄子 尼克 他是迈阿密海滩的警察
Then you can meet Nick, my nephew.He's a policeman in Miami Beach.
为了你 我们愿意 我们只会为你这样做
We'll do it, sir. But only for you.
你们大家给了我新希望
You have all given me new hope.
- 该出发了 长官 - 我们以你为荣
- Way to go, sir. - We're so proud of you.
我虽不能留任 但是我要在学校留下我的风格
If I cannot stay, then I'll go out in style.
迈阿密海滩 准备好了
Miami Beach, get ready.
准备好欢迎艾里克.拉萨德
Get ready for Eric Lassard!
鱼
The fish!
很高兴你重振士气
It's good to have you back, sir.
我向你保证 在我任期内
And I can assure you, this Academy...
绝对不会让你的荣誉受损
under my administration, will no longerbe a source of any embarrassment to you.
- 你已不断地提醒我 - 长官
- Yes, so you keep telling me. - Sir.
整理一下办公室 我的办公室一星期没打扫了
Clean office.My office hasn't been cleaned in a week.
- 管理员已经因为我辞职了 - 对不起 先生
- Janitor quit on me. - Excuse me, sir.
校长 希望你看看我拟的计划
Commissioner, I would like you to look atthis plan that I have formulated.
- 完全全新计划 - 我不是有意打扰你们 长官
- It completely restructures  - I don't mean to bother you, sir!
在现在的学院
...here at the Academy.
哈里斯 你可能是个最称此职的人
Harris, you may Well be the best manfor this position.
你甚至足以当个校长
You may even wind upas commandant of this Academy.
但你必须多学习如何才像个校长
But you sure have a lot to learnabout acting like a commandant.
至少 拉萨德受人尊重 你呢? 有谁尊重你?
At least Lassard has the respectof his men. Whose respect do you have?
- 局长不该这么说你 - 他没错 普卡特
- Commissioner shouldn't have said that. - He's right.
我知道 长官 但...
I know, sir...
他还是...只是他还是不该这样说
but he still shouldn't say it.
不 不 他是对的
No, he's right.
有资格是不足的
Being qualified just isn't enough.
我知道我天生就是做校长的
Now, I know that I was bornto be commandant.
这是我命中注定
It is my destiny.
你和我将去迈阿密海滩
You and I are going to Miami Beach.
- 我们? - 你不明白吗?
- We are? - Don't you see?
我们到迈阿密海滩 协助拉萨德校长
We'll go to Miami Beachand help honor Lassard.
让他知道我有多行
That will show the Commissionerwhat a big man I can be.
- 是 长官 - 打电话去
- Yes, sir. - Get on the phone. Call the airport.
打电话给航空公司预约迈阿密机位
Make a reservation to Miami Beach.
- 头等舱 - 贵宾座
- First class. - VIP.
- 贵宾座 我要新官上任三把火 - 太好了! 长官
- VIP. I'll impress them from the start. - That's brilliant, sir.
琼斯 接电话
Jones, pick up the phone.
起来
Up.
拉萨德什么时候回来?
When's Lassard coming back?
我不知道他不在
I didn't know he was gone.
哈罗! 市立机场
Hello, municipal airport?This is it. Proctor...
我是首都警官学院的哈里斯长官
of the Metropolitan Police Academy.Capt. Harris will be attending...
将出席在迈阿密举行的全国首席警官会议
the NationaI Police Chiefs Conventionin Miami Beach...
我们需要二张一等仓机票搭乘你们闻名于世的航程出国
and will require two first class ticketsaboard your most prestigious flight.
线路忙 请稍等
All lines are busy. Please hold.
普卡特来的电话 他要订二张到迈阿密的一等仓票
I got Proctor on the telephone trying tobook two first - class tickets to Miami...
他以为我是机场人员
for him and Harris.And he thinks I'm the airport.
这正是我们在迈阿密所需要的 哈里斯
Great. Just what we need in Miami, Harris.
不 等一下
No, wait.
请他等几分钟
Put him on hold for a minute.
查询电脑中 请等待
Checking computers right now, sir.Please stand by.
请帮我查一下机票预定电话
I'd like the numberfor Budget Rent a Plane, please.
- 兄弟 离开这! - 好
- Come on, pal. let's go. - Yeah. Okay.
艺术馆
走!
Go!
- 拿去! 老大! - 给
- Here, boss. - Here.
鸭子
Duck.
安静点
Quietly.
我说了安静点
I said quietly.
很好
That's all right.
看! 看看这个
Would you look at this?
慢慢来! 慢慢来
Easy.
蹲下! 笨蛋
Get down, nitwit.
- 嘿! - 晚安
- Hey. - Nighty
好了 行动
All right, let's go.
好了
All right!
- 激光带来没? - 带了
- You got the Laser? - Yeah.
- 拿给我! 快 - 好了! 它热了
- Give it to me. Come on. - Okay, it's hot.
拿着好 拿着
- Here you go. - Sure, here.
来吧
Come to papa.
- 漂亮! 老大 - 看看这宝贝
- Beautiful, boss. - look at that.
卡伦警官
Lt. Callahan.
海塔尔警员
Sgt. Hightower.
琼斯警员
Sgt. Jones.
荷克斯警员
Sgt. Hooks.
塔贝利警员
Sgt. Tackleberry.
康可琳警官
Officer Conklin.
- 谢谢 - 好了! 大家走吧
- Thank you. - All right. let's go.
我们还有点时间 找个酒吧坐坐
We've got some time, boys.What say we find ourselves the bar?
- 当然 老大 - 好主意 老大
- Sure thing, boss. - Yeah. Good idea, boss.
小心,孩子
Watch it, kid!
真准
Yeah. Nice shot.
- 该把这三人绑起来 - 对
- They ought to keep those kids on a leash. - Yeah.
真是白痴
What an idiot.
老大
Boss.
让路
Out of the way, buddy.
老大 你没事吧?
You all right?
- 我头型怎么样? - 很好 老大
- How's my hair? - Beautiful, boss.
让他走 让他走
There he goes, boss.
不要引人注意
let him go.We don't want to draw attention.
是的 钻石才重要
Yeah, the diamonds.
- 确定我的头发没乱? - 和原来一样顺
- Are you sure my hair's all right? - Yeah, it looks the same.
- 怎么样? - 还行 老大
- How's it look? - Hasn't budged, boss.
好 我们走
All right. let's go.
拉萨德局长
Comdt. Lassard...
知道我们不能一起旅行 真遗憾
I was very sorry to learnthat we wouldn't be traveling together.
真是令人失望
Now, that is a disappointment.
普卡特警员为我们订了特别机座
Lt. Proctor has booked uson a very speciaI flight.
贵宾席 抱歉
VIP. Excuse me.
贵宾席 我知道你们订了经济仓
VIP. I understand that you're takingan economy flight.
我们只需在迈阿密碰面就好了 到那儿再见
We'll just have to meet in Miami.I'll see you there.
- 真可惜 - 早上好 先生
- Shame. - Morning, sir.
请小心处理这个包
Please be careful with the bag.
飞行会使他紧张
Flying makes him nervous.
金属物件请拿出
Metal, please.
请再测验一次
Come through again, please.
可能是皮带扣 长官 我来帮您
It's probably the buckle, sir.Here, I'll get it.
把手拿开 普卡特
Get away from me, Proctor.
谢谢
Thank you.
请再测试
Come through, please.
很有趣 琼斯
Very funny, Jones.
普卡特
Hold on. Miss?
请问1545班机在哪儿登机?
Could you please tell me at what gateFlight 1545 is boarding?
- 24号门 - 请确定我们VIP头等仓的机位
- Gate 24, sir. - Could you aIso check and make sure...
名字是哈里斯
that I am in the speciaI VIP section?The name is Harris.
这儿没有VIP仓位 先生 这是私人飞机
There is no VIP section, sir.It's a private plane.
私人飞机
A private plane.
你和普卡特是唯一的登记旅客
And you and Mr. Proctorare the only listed passengers.
我知道了 我们"自己"的飞机
I see. Our own plane.
哈里斯 真是高级旅行
Well, Well, Harris.You travel first - class, I must say.
只有如此了 走 普卡特
Well, it's the only way. Come, Proctor.
- 再见! 祝旅途愉快 - 再见
- Au revoir! Bon voyage! - Ciao!
再见
Auf Wiedersehen.
我的天
Oh, my God!
太好了! 我们自己的飞机 和动物为伍
This is great! Our own airplane.AnimaIs to play with.
我告诉你们VIP的服务 每一分都值得
I'll tell you, this VIP treatmentis worth every penny.
都顺利吧?
A - okay!
普卡特 我怎能忍受你?
Why do I put up with you?
因为我姐姐嫁了你侄子
I think that's becausemy sister married your nephew...
- 那使我们  - 住嘴! 普卡特
- and that makes us  - Shut up, Proctor!
长官 他们喜欢你
Sir, they like you!
- 先生 你用什么饮料? - 现在不用 谢谢
- Sir, what would you like to drink today? - Nothing right now, thank you.
喷雾剂不再像以前那像令我着迷
Trichloroethane just doesn't havethe appeaI for me that it used to have.
我还是依靠"PR-24"
I still depend on the old PR-24.
这个小东西 根本不会断 可以把东西敲碎
This little baby, it doesn't even break.It pulverizes.
我能打滥任何人 窒死任何人
I can smash anybody.I can hold them in a chokehold.
我能制服任何罪犯或犯罪集团
I have complete control over a perpetratoror a group of perpetrators.
有一次 我遇见三个家伙从我左边袭来
One time, when I saw these three guyscoming on from the left....
眼睛向左
Eyes left!
海塔尔 看看这个
Hightower, check this out.
- 你看到什么 房子? - 是有关蒙伦的报导
- What you got there, House? - There's an article here on Malone.
- 我一点也不喜欢他 - 告诉我你的理由
- I don't even like him. - Give me five points.
- 你明白的 - 对不起 先生
- You got it. - Excuse me, sir...
能不能回到你座位上?
would you mind returningto your own seat?
- 正餐就要上了 - 正餐?
- We're about to serve the meal. - The meal?
- 秩序很乱 - 让我进去! 让我进去
- Out of order. - let me in here.
你等很久了? 很好! 她在
You've been waiting long?Great. She's been....
快点! 快点! 还有人想进去
Come on! Other people in need here,you know.
抱歉
Sorry.
抱歉! 马桶出问题了
I'm sorry. There seems to besomething wrong with the sink.
我不相信 竟和他同机
I don't believe it. We're on the same plane.
- 老大! 我们该 - 你疯了吗?
- Boss, you know, we should.... - What, are you crazy?
- 我们带了这个不能 - 轮流来
- We can't make a scene while we got.... - Wait for your turn.
快! 让我进去 让我进去
Come on. let me in.
让我出来 让我出来
let me out of here!
- 天 我要杀了他 - 不 老大
- I'll kill him! - No, boss!
- 钻石 老大 - 对
- The diamonds, boss. - Right.
来! 拿着这个
Here. Fix this.
- 对不起 先生 你的雪茄 - 有什么问题? 小姐
- Please, sir. Your cigar. - You got a problem, Lady?
- 对不起 先生 - 又有什么事?
- Excuse me. - Now what?
- 干得好! 贺克斯 - 当然
- Okay, nice touch, Hooks. - Yeah!
女士们先生们 谢谢各位搭乘此机
Ladies and gentlemen,thank you for flying with us.
祝你在迈阿密过得开心
We hope you enjoy your stayin the Miami area.
现在的气温正是宜人的28摄氏度
The temperature is a balmy 82 degrees.
我不知道怎么回事? 大概卡住了
I don't know what's the matter.It must be stuck.
我去找人来帮忙
I'll get some help.
- 只要一下于就好了! 各位 - 要帮她吗?
- It'll just be a minute or so, folks. - Shall we help her?
- 好吧 - 请让一下 小姐
- let's do it. - Excuse me, ma'am.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你 先生
Why, thank you, gentlemen.
可以下机了
You may all deplane now.
请注意 183次航班...
Attention, please.Passengers on Flight 183...
从迈阿密到加拉加斯的乘客
continuing from Miami to Caracas...
因为小故障航班晚点
there will be a slight delaydue to a small malfunction.
我们把钻石送过去之后 在城里待一晚...
After we deliver the diamonds,a night on the town. Your treat.
离那老头子远一点! 他是衰鬼 保持距离
Stay the hell away from that old man.He's bad Luck. Keep your distance.
他是个大衰鬼 好了! 可以轻松了
He's a bucket of bad news.All right, now we can relax.
- 没事吧! 老大 你还好吧? - 没事 没事
- You okay, boss? You all right, boss? - Yeah.
- 包! 包! - 我去拿
- The bag. - I'll get it.
- 拿到了 - 我没事
- I got it. - I'm all right.
- 走吧! 把带子给我 - 在你那呢
- Give me the damn bag. - You got it.
我们快走 我还要同别人会面
let's get the hell out of here.I got people to meet.
- 这是什么? - 像白痴大会
- What the hell is this? - looks like a moron convention.
- 那一对番木果真不赖 - 他来了
- That's a nice set of papayas. - There he is.
我已恭读过你的记录
I've read of your accomplishments,and I must say that our city...
本市诚致欢迎十年度最佳警官
is proud to welcomethe Police Officer of the Decade.
- 你真好 市长先生 - 这是警察局长 大卫莫达
- You're very, very kind, Mr. Mayor. - Our Police Commissioner, Dave Murdock.
他是这些警察大会主席
He's in charge ofthe Police Chiefs Convention.
- 很荣幸见到你 大卫 - 我很荣幸见到你 拉萨德校长
- Very, very pleased to meet you, Dave. - Pleasure's all mine, Comdt. Lassard.
汤普森市长
Mayor Thompson, I'd like you to meet...
这位是拉萨德校长的警政总监亨利哈斯特
Comdt. Lassard'sPolice Commissioner, Henry Hurst.
你好
How do you do?
这些人 大卫 都是我最优秀的下属
And these, Dave, are my finest.
欢迎各位长官
Good to have you here, officers.
站住! 停
Stop! Halt!
- 你好 尼克 - 你好 艾里克叔叔
- Good to see you, Nick. - Hi, Uncle Eric.
那是我经常说到的侄子尼克 我很为他感到骄傲
That's my nephew, NickI was talking about. I'm very proud of him.
怎么回事? 你在做什么?
What's the matter? What are you doing?
- 这是你的钱包 先生 - 谢谢你! 警官
- Here's your wallet, sir. - Thank you, Officer.
不客气
You're very welcome.
你好 艾里克叔叔
Good to see you, Uncle Eric.
我一直在期待看见你
I've looked forward to this so much.
尼克 他们都是我最优秀的下属 我最好的朋友
Nick, I want you to meet my finest,my best friends.
对不起 比尔
Excuse me. Bill?
校长 这是我太大 爱玲
Comdt. Lassard, this is my wife, Eileen...
我们欢迎委员会的主席
the chairwomanof our welcoming committee.
- 非常荣幸见到你 - 你好
- Very pleased to meet you. - How do you do?
我们所有人都接到了 除了哈里斯队长
We've greeted everyone except Capt. Harris.
- 我们到处找不到他人 - 他马上会来的
- We can't find him anywhere. - He'll be along shortly.
他搭私人飞机过来
He's traveling by private plane.
是不是很好玩 长官?
Isn't this fun, sir?
他们看起来很羡慕 我们该带只大象来的
They look impressed, sir.I wish we had an elephant.
喝点什么吗?
Would you like something?
你的货 先生
Your merchandise, sir.
- 你拿到钻石了? - 是的! 先生 照你交待的
- You got the diamonds? - Yes, sir. We did like you told us.
我们拿出钻石 把垃圾金块扔掉了
We tore out the stonesand threw that gold junk away.
- 好! 好 - 我们从四处的摄像机下面走过来了
- Good. - We hid them in the camera.
这是个礼品包
It's gift-wrapped.
- 这是玩笑吗? - 先生?
- Is this some kind of joke? - Sir?
我没什么好说的 被人掉了包了
I got no excuse, sir.Somebody pulled a bag switch on me.
我的船24小时内要离开这个国家
My boat leaves the country in 24 hours.
- 那是你最后期限 - 是的! 先生
- You got till then. - Yes, sir.
- 别再让我失望了 - 谢谢你! 丹西先生
- Don't disappoint me again. - Thank you, Mr. Dempsey.
妈的
Shit!
那老疯子拿了我们的袋子
That crazy old man has our bag! All right.
搜查每一家旅馆 找出他为止
We search every hotel untiI we find him.
要是明天之前不找回钻石 我们就死定了
If we don't get those diamonds backthis time tomorrow, we're dead.
- 大卫 这旅行办得很好 - 谢谢! 局长
- You give a fine tour, David. - Thank you, Commissioner.
莫达克局长 你对今年警察游行程序
Commissioner Murdock,what have you got planned...
有没有什么计划?
as police procedure demonstrationthis year?
去年 他们把队长级以上的人全逮捕了
Last year, they arrested everyoneabove the rank of captain, put us all in jaiL.
很好笑吧
It was all rather fun, really.
先别提这个 要是我说了就制造不出意外惊喜了
Comdt. Lassard, if I told you,it would spoil the surprise.
我带你们看看娱乐场
let me show you the pool areaand the rest of the hotel...
我们主要活动都在那里举行
where most our conventionwill take place.
那照片很好
It's a good picture.
我想制服表现出了我最好的一面
I guess the uniformbrings out the best in me.
艾里克 你还好吗?
Uncle Eric, are you all right?
我真的会怀念这一切的
I'm really going to miss all this.
试音 1 2 3 4 试音 你听得见吗?
Testing, one, two, three, four.Testing, can you hear me?
可以吗?
Is that okay?
这次大会一定很棒! 控制好群众游行
This is going to be a great convention.They got crowd control demonstrations...
新装备 军事战技
new equipment, martial arts.
还有 你看 炸弹清除介绍
And, look, a bomb disposal presentation.
- 你们做秀真好 - 是呀!
- You guys put on a good show. - Yes, sir, we do.
不过要下午才开始
But it doesn't start untiI this afternoon.So this morning...
所以 早上先带你到沙滩看另一场美丽的表演
I would like you to see another showon a beautifuI stretch of beach.
当然 游泳池也很不错的
Of course, the pool is nice, too.
失陪一下 可以吗?
Pardon me, won't you?
小姐们请注意 水上有氧课程15分钟后开始
Attention, ladies, the water aerobics classwill begin in 15 minutes.
表演一下
Show us how.
池畔按摩师
Poolside masseur.
我知道了
I see.
- 玩得愉快吗? - 非常愉快 谢谢!你呢
- Enjoying yourself? - Very much so. Thank you. And you?
我也是
Oh, yeah.
我喜欢陌生人把手放在我身上
I just love it when a strange manputs his hands all over my body.
真的?
You do?
- 这正好给我机会做这个 - 不! 等一下
- It gives me a chance to do this. - No, wait.
游客请注意 水上有氧课程15分钟后开始
Attention, guests, the water aerobics classwill begin in 15 minutes.
- 我想我应该 - 不过 很好玩
- So I guess I deserved that. - But it was fun.
高塔
Hightower, okay, here we go. Come on.
- 我到远点去接 好吗? - 好! 开始
- I'll go out for a long one, okay? - Okay, here we go.
好 传过来
Okay, come on.
快 好! 开始了
Here we go, come on.
我接一个! 来呀
I'll buy one. Okay, here we go! Come on!
怎么了? 没手吗? 好呀
What's the matter, no arm? Okay!
安德鲁 甜心
Andrew, honey!
过来 拿你的防晒油
Come on. Come get your sun block.
救命!
Help!
鲨鱼!
Shark!
尼基! 马上离开这游泳区 小子
Desist and leave the swimming area now, mister.
那家伙在于什么?
What's that guy doing?
快走! 快走! 快走
Move it.
马上!
Now!
打得好! 房子
Way to go, House!
做好日光浴的秘密就是控制得宜
The secret to a great tan is control.
首先 我使用这4号日照油可照出一旁金黄肤色
First, I use this Number 4 tanning lotionto give myself a nice golden brown.
然后用防晒油隔离阳光刺激 以免皮肤受伤
Then I use a complete sun blockto keep those dangerous rays off my skin.
丢过来 给我
Throw it here, to me.
- 有个呆瓜挡住了我的阳光 - 哈里斯队长 我不知道你在这
- Some dickhead is standing in my sun. - Captain Harris, I didn't see you there.
我想你还不认识我 我是
I don't think we've been introduced
我不管你是谁? 屁眼 只要你别挡住我的阳光
I don't care who you are, but twipe.Just get out of my sun.
- 屁眼? - 混蛋! 呆子
- Buttwipe? - Scram, sleazeball!
好吧! 很好
Okay. Fine.
屁眼? 很长时间没听到了
Buttwipe? Haven't heard that in a while.
- 太棒了! 长官 - 普卡特
- That was great, sir. - Proctor.
-什么事? 长官 - 现在是你挡住我阳光了
- Yes, sir. - Now you're in my sun.
防晒油借一下 凯特
let me have your sun block, Kate.
他要去哪儿?
Where's he going?
你脚是这么踏的吗?
Is this how your feet fit in these things?
我没玩过这个 这可是我第一次
I've never done this before.This is my first time!
所以 我没挥手前 别乱动好吗
So, don't do anythinguntiI I wave my hand, okay?
- 随便 - 你听到了吗?
- Whatever. - You got that?
停
Stop!
对不起
Excuse me!
没关系
Never mind!
谢谢 我也想那样
Thanks. I meant to do that, too.
谢谢! 谢谢
Thanks. Thank you.
- 很棒吧 - 我的天
- Pretty good? - Oh, my God!
你好 王八
Hello, dork.
怎么了? 王八
What's happening, dork?
看看这个家伙
Check that guy out.
丽沙 你做得很棒! 绝无疑问
You do good work, lisa.No question about it.
市长先生 对不起 我不是存心侮辱你这城市
Mr. Mayor, excuse me, sir.I don't mean to insult your city...
但这沙滩上的人都非常无礼
but the people on this beachare very rude and hostile.
那我真是抱歉 王八队长
I'm sorry to hear that, Capt. Dork.
他是个高个 大概这么高 有着白发 提个高尔夫球袋
He's an old guy about this tall,with white hair, always carries a golf bag.
- 你见过他吗? - 他也不在这旅馆
- You haven't seen him? - He ain't at this hotel either.
我们死定了 死定了
We are dead men.Three dead men, that's who we are.
- 你们他妈的上哪去了? - 我们在找你们
- Where the hell have you guys been? - We was at the track.
- 丹尼先生找不到我们 - 他很不安 你知道吗?
- Mr. Dempsey couldn't find us. - He was very upset, you know.
- 你们要吃甜甜圈吗? - 我们一定能找到那老家伙
- Any of you guys want a doughnut? - We got to find this old guy!
马上就天黑了
It's going to be dark soon.
可以给我们两杯番茄汁吗?
Can we geta couple of those potato coladas?
什么?
What?
我要一个粉红 不 绿色的伞
Could I get a pink....No, make it a green umbrella.
喝呀! 长官 喝干
Drink up, sir. Bottoms up.
- 能给我一份蝗虫吗? - 你好
- May I have a grasshopper, please? - Hi, how are you?
势利
What a snob.
势利? 看看你自己的德性 呆瓜
Snob? Take a look at yourself,you first - class schmuck.
零钱 给我些零钱
Change. Give me some change.
- 天蝎座 对吧? - 不是
- Scorpio, right? - No.
长官 我可以要根雪茄吗?
Sir, can I get a cigar?
-天秤座? - 不是
- libra? - No.
- 你很漂亮 - 谢谢
- You're a very pretty Lady. - Thanks.
肤色也很健美
That's a nice suntan.
我今天也晒了些日光浴
I got a little suntan today, too.
很好
That's nice.
也许你待会儿会想到我房间去涂一些乳液
Maybe you'd like to come up to my roomLater and put a little lotion on it.
不要吗? 看你这可爱的雀斑 你叫什么名字? 小女孩
No? look at these cute freckles.What is your name, little girl?
你在于什么? 吹我耳朵?
What are you doing, blowing in my ear?
- 不 长官 我  - 快滚
- No, sir  - Scram!
我的名字是泰第斯.哈里斯 你也许听说过
My name is Thaddeus Harris.May be you've heard of me.
没听过
Not really.
快灭火
Put it out!
不要
Don't.
我想 上我房间去是没问题的了
I guess coming up to my roomis out of the question.
女人 不可理瑜
Women. Go figure.
我不会告诉任何人
I won't tell anyone.
是假炸弹恐吓 抢劫? 我感到越来越兴奋
Is it a mock bomb threat?A robbery? Am I getting warm?
艾里克 我不告诉你有关警察演习的事
Eric, I'm not telling you anythingabout the police procedure demonstration.
- 你只要等着看就好了 - 好吧!
- You're just going to have to wait and see. - Oh, Well....
你一定会有个好演习 大卫 谢谢你告诉我
You have a fine operation, David.Thank you for showing it to me.
我的荣幸 对不起让我们都迟到了
My pleasure, Eric.I'm just sorry that I made us run Late.
好! 好
All right.
我们要找遍所有的旅馆的房间
Between us,we've covered every hotel on hotel row.
你们 你们从南滩开始
You guys. I want you guysto start South Beach.
我们没在这里见到他 我们从北边开始
We don't see him here,we'll start Northside...
向你们这里来 明白吗?
and work our way to you. You got it?
明白就走吧
You got it? Okay, get out of here.
你用油炸酱喷我 白痴
You squirted me with your doughnut, moron!
- 你真令人想吐 你这只猪 - 老大 我抱歉
- You are disgusting. You are such a pig! - Boss, I'm sorry.
你们这些人都是猪
You guys are such pigs.
我们最好快进去! 老大
We better go right on in.
是他
That's him!
快 等什么?
Come on, get out of here!What're you waiting for?
对不起 白痴
Excuse us, Gunga Din.
- 白痴  - 老大在哪里?
- Yeah, Gunga. - Where's the boss?
- 他在那 老大  - 看到了吗?
- He's right there, boss. - He's right over there, boss.
我们抓了他马上出来 尽量小声 不得已时用武力 明白吗?
We grab him. We get out. Quiet if we can,rough if we have to. You got it?
- 明白 老大 - 我抓那个大块头的
Got it, boss. I'll take the big guy.
- 都是大块头  - 那个白发的
- Both are big guys. - I'll take the guy with white hair.
都是白发
Both got white hair.
- 我抓左边的 - 你的左边
- I'll take the left. - Your left
- 闭嘴 - 老大
- Would you shut up? - All right, boss.
- 明白了? - 明白 老大
- You got it? - Got it boss.
进来吧! 来登记吧
Come on in and register.
对不起 走错了
Sorry, wrong room.
祝各位好运
Best of Luck.
蓝卡是午餐会通行证
The blue card is your Lunch pass.
- 老大 他是警察 - 我们死定了 老大
- Boss, he's a cop! - We're dead men, boss.
- 老板  - 别吵 我必须想想
- Boss! - Shut up. I gotta think.
你们两个去洗洗好吗? 真厌恶
Would you two guys clean yourselves up?You're disgusting!
他是警察
He's a cop.
让我们的鱼儿出去晒晒太阳
Come on, Birdie.let's get our little fish a little sunshine.
我的小鱼儿呢?
Where's my little fish?
鸟儿! 你在哪?
Birdie, where are you?
他们怎么可以这样?
They shouldn't have.
太棒了
Splendid!
出来!
Come on out.
饭店洗衣服务 先生
Hotel Laundry service, sir.
有没有东西清洗的?
You got anything you wantdry cleaned or Laundered?
- 今天没有 谢谢 - 太好了 先生
- Nothing today, thank you. - Very good, sir.
这礼物可真大有可为
This present has real possibilities.
你在这儿 你这顽皮的小鱼
There you are, you naughty, naughty fish.
我想让他帮我弄点蓝的
I was thinking of having himput a little more blue in it....
来吧
Come on.
小菜一碟 老板
A piece of cake, boss.
什么?
What?
看看里面有什么
What have we got here?
摄影机在哪里?
Where is the camera?
班比穿了这套可爱的伪装高射炮背心后
And Bambi's not going to take any flak...
就不需再拿什么高射炮了
when she wearsthis lovely camouflage flak vest.
你想试穿吗? 先生
Would you care to try it on, sir?
手拷! 莱尼 你看 小心
Handcuffs. Laverne, look, restraints.
对不起! 小姐 抱歉! 小姐
Excuse me, miss. Pardon me, miss?
对不起!
Excuse me.
- 抱歉! - 逃兵
- Pardon me  - Hooks.
你试试这个不更好吗?
Why don't you try this?
这个会更有效
This works even better!
闪开
Out of my way.
你什么时候看到他走的?
So when you see him, go....
你知道我意思吗? 好
You know what I mean? Okay.
就这个人 明白吗?
This is the guy, all right?
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿! 王八
Hey, dork.
别错过了最新的警察配件
Don't miss the Latestin police holds and grips.
分别在五个场地展出
They will be demonstratedon five different mats.
在现场有专家示范
We have experts demonstratingtechniques in...
柔道 空手道 胎拳道
judo, aikido, Taekwon  Do,hapkido, and karate.
- 嘿 卡拉汉 - 尼克!
- Hey, Callahan. - Nick.
好厉害!
Excellent technique.
- 那是凯特吗? - 对
- Is that Kate? - Yeah.
- 你不晓得她会这些? - 我根本不知道她是个警察
- You didn't know she could do that? - Didn't even know she was a cop.
他在哪?
Where is he?
- 把带子割掉! - 我正努力
- Cut the strap! - I'm trying.
不要
Don't!
- 快 把相机抢过来! - 好! 好
- Come on, just get the camera. - Okay.
- 又让他跑了 - 翻过围栅
- Missed him again. - Go round the wall.
下一位自愿者 要和我一起示范球口
With our next volunteer,we will demonstrate the chokehold.
我们全力将他扫倒
We take him down with a sweep down.
要是他还抵抗
If he becomes aggressive...
我们抓住他的手 转过来
we take his arm, turn him around...
顶着腹部丢出去
into the stomach throw.
下一位!
Next?
我接受你的挑战
I accept your challenge.
好的
Okay.
看看你的本领 琼斯
let's see what you got, Jonesey.
好 你先上
All right, you're on.
很好
Very good.
谢谢
Thank you.
下一位!
Next.
琼斯 看 是刀子
Jones, look at that. It's a knife.
- 看我的 - 她是说刀子吗?
- Watch this! - Did she say knife?
兄弟! 让我拉你起来 来!
Brother, let me help you up.
对初学者来说很不错了
Not bad for a beginner.
漂亮的动作! 下一位
What a good sport. Next.
是我吗? 小姐
That's it for me, Lady.
快! 别害怕
Come on, don't be afraid.
- 借过! 借过! - 他是自告奋勇的
- Make way. - Here's a volunteer.
局长! 这大会太棒了
Commissioner, fabulous convention.
- 太棒了! 长官 - 没错
- Fabulous, sir. - Good.
这大会真棒
This is a great convention.
下一位! 我需要一位自告奋勇人
Next. I need a volunteer.
谢谢
Thanks.
翻个筋斗
Upsy - daisy.
没事 没事 我很好
That's okay, I'm all right.
- 谢谢! - 下一位
- Thank you. - Next.
一个有权威性的声音对群众运动的控制是很重要的
An authoritative voiceis very important in crowd control.
现在让我们找些人出来表演表演
Now, let's see how some of you peopledo in this situation.
警官! 请出来
Officer, out here with me.
群众正冲破警方防线
The crowd has just broken throughyour police line.
叫他们回去
Move them back.
不! 不! 我们不走
Hell, no! We won't go!
- 怎么了? 你以为我会伤害你? - 对!
- What's the matter. You think I'll hurt you? - Yeah.
记得我教你的动作 好吗?
Just remember what I taught you, okay?
- 温和点 - 好!
- Be gentle. - Okay.
我想我大概做错了
I guess I did that wrong.
我不知道! 这技巧有它的好处
I don't know.This technique has its merits.
- 那 我们可再试一次吗? - 熟能生巧
- Shall we try it again? - Practice makes perfect.
警官! 该你了 请出列
Officer, your turn. Out here with me.
不 不 我们不走
Hell, no! We won't go!
对不起! 我们必需保持
Excuse me. We need to keep it....
请帮帮忙 退后一点好吗?
It would really help us a lotif you'll just back up.
退后! 混蛋
Back off, you turkeys!
我是警官 我说话 你们就得听
I'm a police officer,and when I talk, you listen!
现在赶紧给我他妈的退后 免得我发火
Now, get your butts the hell back therebefore I really get mad!
不准回嘴
And no back talk!
- 我们得跳下去? 那是他吗? - 对! 是他!
- We jump out of this. That's him? - Yeah. Go out on the limb.
抓住他
let's get him.
- 他去哪里了?  - 我们怎么没碰到地?
- Where'd he go? - How come we haven't hit the ground yet?
这是物理现象
Physics.
- 具有活力呀 - 枪法很准 警官
- Way to zing there, Officer. - Very, very nice shooting, Officer.
好枪法! 好枪法
Excellent shooting! Excellent!
警官 你得把枪分给别人一些
Officer, you need to share those weaponswith the other officers.
不! 我全要
No. I need these.
我来跟他谈
let me talk to him.
我们回家后 我会帮你弄一些
I'll get you some of your very ownjust as soon as we get home.
- 你保证? - 绝对保证
- You promise? - Cross my heart.
- 好! - 太好了
- Okay. - Good.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢
- Thank you very much. - Thank you.
尤金! 这一只也一样
Eugene, this one, too.
我们走吧
let's go.
- 谢谢 我们走吧 - 打扰了
Thank you. let's go, guys. Excuse me.
我想访问一下两位
May I have an interview, please?
3 2 1  哈罗! 你是?
On three, two, one, guys.Hello, and you are?
市府警局沙提斯哈里斯队长
Capt. Thaddeus Harrisof the Metropolitan Police Department.
只是一个队长而已? 停 走吧
Only a captain? Cut. Out of here.
- 他不是大人物  - 看来像侍者
- He's a nobody. - He looks like a waiter.
- 长官  - 别说话
- Sir  - Not a word, Proctor.
好
All right. Okay.
我们的24小时快用完了
Our 24 hours are almost gone.
我们现在必须夺回那摄影机
We got to get that camera back now!
为什么要用五个壮汉去夺一个老头子的摄影机?
Why do we need five guysto take a camera from one old man?
- 相信我 没那么容易  - 对
- Believe me, it ain't that easy. - Yeah.
好 各位 我们来试试这一招
Boys, I want you totry this one on for size.
我们假定我们经过那老头子旁旁
let's just saywe happen to be passing by...
而他正好昏过去
and the poor old guy happens to faint.
老鼠和小唐刚好扶住他让他卧下
Mouse, Sugar, they happen to catch him.They set him down on the ground.
把他的衣领解开
Maybe they open his collar.
也许可以利用时间把摄影机拿走
Maybe they slip thatnasty camera off his neck.
- 你的计划真棒 老大  - 真好
- That is a great plan, boss. - Very good.
如果那老头子昏倒了
If the old man faints.
他会昏倒的
He'll faint.
胡里欧可以保证 来 胡里欧 给他们看一下
Julio will make sure of that.Go on, Julio, show them.
我们给他一针 让他今晚好睡
We'll give him a shot,make him go night-night.
- 这计划不错 老大  - 很棒
- That's a pretty good plan, boss. - That's great.
- 好 我们走吧  - 走
- Come on, let's get out of here. - All right.
快,小唐
Come on, Sugar.
我们只有十分钟
We only have about 10 more minutes of this.
- 拉萨德 恭喜你  - 谢谢你
- Lassard, congratulations! - Thank you so much.
让我来  好了
let me just.... Here you go.
局长 你向拉萨德校长道贺
Commissioner, could I get a picture...
我来拍照好吗
of you congratulating Comdt. Lassard?
- 当然可以  - 谢谢
- Of course, certainly. Yes. - Thank you.
有机会照个相了
Photo opportunity.
留在这里
Stay.
谢谢
Thank you.
校长 我要向你道贺
Commandant, I just want to say helloand congratulations.
我们下次会成功的 老大 交给我们办就好
We'll get him next time, boss.We'll see to it. We'll get it.
又不是我的错
It wasn't our fault.
对不起
Excuse me.
请你把我的摄影机给我
Would you just give me my damn camera?
- 我的摄影机? - 把我摄影机还我
- My camera? - Give me my damn camera!
- 那是什么? - 钻石 钻石
- What are those? - Diamonds!
- 你把我的摄影机弄坏了 - 钻石
- You broke my camera. - Diamonds!
好 好
All right! All right!
都不要动 否则这老头子会作古
Nobody move, or the old man is history.
- 老大 - 什么? 什么?
- Boss. - What?
好 手举高 所有人的手都举高
All right. I want to see hands in the air.Everybody's hands up.
快 举起来
Now. Hands up!
扶他起来 我要看到每一个人
Pick him up.I want everybody where I can see them.
- 拿钻石 快拿 - 我明白了
- Get the diamonds. - I see.
是警察演习
The police procedure demonstration.
绑架 具有创意
A kidnapping. How original.
- 我真感到荣幸  - 别吵 老头
- I am honored. - Shut up, old man.
是 真抱歉
Yes, of course. I'm sorry.
我们现在进电梯
Now, we make for the elevator.
任何人别想乱来 不然洋旁都会是弹坑
Anybody gets stupid,he gets filled full of holes.
警察 别动
Police, freeze!
到上面掩护我 快过去
Cover me up top! let's go!
快过来 把人质放掉
All right, release your hostage...
武器放在地上 手慢慢地举高
put your weapons on the ground,and slowly put your hands in the air!
说的好 那是我的侄子
Well said! That's my nephew.
- 别吵 老头子  - 好了 先生 手举高
- Shut up, old man. - Okay, mister, hands up!
你好
Hi.
你们都别想开枪 只要我手中有这老爷在
Nobody's gonna shoot.Not while I got grandpa here.
- 现在 - 太晚了
- Now! - Too Late!
老鼠 小唐 进电梯
Mouse, Sugar, get in the elevator!
- 都别动 - 他在吓人的 是不是?
- Nobody move! - No, no. He's bluffing, right?
很聪明 他只是在吓人
Smart boy. He was bluffing.
他只是在吓人 老大
He was bluffing, boss.
好 哪一层? 哪一层?
All right! What floor?
怎么了? 你不喜欢这一层吗?
What's the matter?You got a problem with this floor?
我不想干预 但局长他们在楼下
I don't mean to interfere,but the commissioners are all downstairs.
要是我 我会到阁楼去 那里易守难攻
I would use the penthouse.It's very defensible.
我也欢迎各位用我的套房 让我来好了
You're all welcome to use my suite.Allow me.
怎么了?
What?
到了
Here we are.
我准备好了
All right, I'm ready.
快拿蓝图来 时间不多了
Snap it up with those blueprints.We don't have all day.
- 拿来了 长官 - 谢谢
- Here you are, sir. - Thank you.
塔贝利 你不要一直弄那个好吗
Tackleberry, would you pleasestop doing that?
对不起 长官
Sorry, sir.
好 好
All right.
现在 他们一定会答应我们一切要求
Now, they're gonnagive us anything we want.
所以我们只要想办法以最快的速度到丹西的船上
So all we got to do is figure outthe fastest way to get to Dempsey's boat.
- 我口渴了 老大 - 你这里有没有酒?
- I'm thirsty, boss. - You got any booze around here?
- 当然 酒吧内应有尽有  - 谢谢
- Certainly. The bar's very well-stocked. - Thanks.
冰箱里大概还有冰淇淋
There might still besome ice cream left in the freezer.
谢谢 你真会待客
Thanks. You're really a good host.
你真客气
You're very welcome.
拜托好吗?
Do you mind?
我们是要计划逃离这里呀
Some of us are trying toplan our escape here.
对不起 老大
Sorry, boss.
我们需要在港口弄到船
We are definitely gonna needa boat at the harbor.
然后我们要在旅馆后门进入
And we're definitely gonna needa fast car at the hotel back entrance.
怎么了?
What?
我们可以很容易到达屋顶 只有呆子不会想到要直升机
With the roof so accessible,you'd be a fool not to ask for a helicopter.
直升机? 真傻
Helicopter? What a stupid idea!
不 他说的对
No. He's right.
在车上会被他们追击 直升机是个好主意
We'd be a sitting duck in that car.The chopper is a great idea.
- 好 我们坐直升机到港口 - 然后呢?
- We take the chopper to the harbor  - And?
然后 然后我们上船
Then we switch to the boat!
怎么? 你不喜欢船是吗?
What? You don't like the boat?
- 怎么? - 怎么?
- What? - What?
我必须去下洗手间
I have to go to the little boys' room.
不 这是绑架呀 这不是幼儿园
No, this is a kidnapping!It's not a kindergarten!
老大 直升机是他想到的
Boss, he did think of the helicopter.
对 老大 行行好吧
Yeah. Come on, boss.
好 好
All right, fine.
但要快点 我们还要打电话
But make it quick.Got a phone call to make here.
好 好
All right.
我们现在只能等他们的要求了
All we can do nowis wait untiI we hear their demands.
你大概对 现在只能等了
I'm afraid you're right.All we can do now is wait.
那个人把哈里斯叫醒好吗?
Would someone please wake Harris up?
他在思考
He's thinking.
好 来 开口 张大一点
Here we go, come on. Open up. Big aah.
请你不要弄那个好吗?
Would you please stop doing that?
对不起 长官
Sorry, sir.
内部电话 长官
Incoming call for you, sir.
- 哈罗  - 好 听着 注意听
- Hello. - All right. listen up.
我要一架带驾驶员的直升机到楼顶
I want a helicopter with piloton the roof of this hotel.
然后呢?
And?
我再要一只快艇在港口等我
And I want a fast boatwaiting for me in the harbor.
如果一切顺利 我看不到有警察
If all goes Well, I see no cops...
只要我们到达国际水域后 我就会把老头子留在西钥匙岛
I hand the old man back to youat the 12 - mile mark off Key West...
12里的标线附近
as soon as we're safein internationaI waters.
我们要求证拉萨德是否还活着
We want some proofthat Lassard is still alive.
你的朋友找你讲话
Your buddies want to talk to you.
- 哈罗  - 拉萨德校长吗?
- Hello? - Comdt. Lassard?
哈斯特局长 你能打电话来真好
Commissioner Hurst,how nice of you to call.
我真的希望你能尽一切力量救我
I do hope that you do your bestto rescue me.
这样会更为刺激
It'll only make the whole thingall the more exciting.
别担心 艾里克叔叔 我们会救你出来的
Don't worry, Uncle Eric,we'll get you out of this.
他还活着 至于能活多久就要看你们如何做了
All right. He's alive.How long, depends on you.
我想拉萨德是在告诉我们
I think, in his own way,Lassard is telling us...
他宁愿牺牲也不愿让那些人逃走
that he'd rather risk his own lifethan let those animaIs get away.
真是个勇敢的人
Brave man.
长官 我知道这是你的权力
Sir. I realize that this is your jurisdiction...
但如果需要有救援人员 我们自愿去
but if there's going to be a rescue attempt,we'd like to volunteer.
莫拉局长 我极为赞同
Commissioner Murdock,I couldn't agree more.
我认为救援人员一定要很熟悉拉萨德校长
I think it is vitaI that the rescue teamknow Comdt. Lassard intimately.
我可以为这些警官的能力作担保
I can vouch for the skillof these police officers.
毕竟是我亲自训练他们的
After all, I trained them myself.
他一定是吃错药了
It must be the drugs.
好 这一层是拉萨德被劫持的地方
This is the floorwhere Lassard is being held hostage.
- 哈里斯队长  - 什么事?
- Capt. Harris? - Yes?
好 各位 这就是我要你们做的
All right, gentlemen.This is what I want you to do.
你们必须完全照我的话做
And you will do itexactly as I tell you to do it.
你现在是在收听的是KWURST电台
You've tuned to Larvell Joneson the KWURST Radio.
我是"爱情博士" 来吧 宝贝
And, now, the love Doctor.I want you to come here, baby.
你和我 享受吧
You and me, yeah. All the way.
来吧! 宝贝 因为我需要你
Come on down. let's get down, baby,because I need you. I love you.
今天播音结束
That concludes our broadcast day.
为什么我必须走楼梯上来?
How come I got the part with the steps?
我给你路走了
I offered you the vent.
不必了
No.
走
let's go.
漂亮 凯特 看招
Nice, Kate. Watch this.
"请勿打扰"
女人总是忙不完
A woman's work is never done.
快来
Come on.
你顺利进来了
That went off without a hitch.
人都到哪里去了?
Where is everybody?
我不明白
I don't get it.
直升机来了
The chopper's here already.
一个小时之内不可能到的
It wasn't supposed to be here for an hour.
- 一定有人改变主意了 - 对 是哈里斯
- Someone must have changed the plans. - Yeah, Harris.
你的计划真棒 长官
Your plan was brilliant, sir!
谢谢你 普卡持
Thank you, Proctor.
我给那些没能力的人牵制计划
By giving those incompetentsthe diversionary part of this mission...
我把真正的救援计划交给有经验的警官
I've left the real rescueto the experienced officers...
也就是 我
namely, moi.
我会救出拉萨德 然后升职 拿勋章
I will rescue Lassard,and I'll get a promotion and a medal.
- 别动 - 别动
- Freeze! - Freeze!
- 我们是警察 你们已被包围 - 干的好 哈里斯
- We've got you covered. This is the police. - Well done, Harris!
这是我的荣幸 长官 每个人都把枪丢下
It was my pleasure, sir.Now, everyone, drop your guns!
- 快 下去拿枪 - 是 长官
- Proctor, get down there and pick them up. - Yes, sir.
不 不 普卡特 梯子 用梯子
No, Proctor, no. Use the Ladder.The Ladder!
好 好 来 人给我
All right! Come on, give it to me.
对 手举起来 否则你死定了
That's right. Hands up,or you've got one dead dork.
高潮起伏 今年他们全部出动了是不是?
Nice twist. They're really going all outthis year, aren't they?
带他们上直升机 我要到船那里去
Get these guys to the chopper.All right, I'm going to my boat.
在我们和我的人会合之前 我如果看到一架飞机
Tell your people,I see one plane, one chopper, one boat...
直升机或一只船 这些人就会成为沙鱼饵了 明白吗?
before we reach our rendezvous,these guys are shark bait. You got it?
- 哈里斯呢? - 也被绑架了
- Where's Harris? - They kidnapped him, too.
现在我们按照我们的方法行事
From now on, we do it our way.
我们需要更多情报
We'll need some more information.
我什么都不知道
I don't know nothing.
原来如此 我告诉你 兄弟
I see. I'll tell you, partner...
别对我说 你对他说
don't tell me. Tell him.
老大叫我们在这里等 他去看直升机来了没有
The boss said to wait here while he checked on the chopper.
后来你们就出现了 我只知道这些
Then you guys showed up,and that's all I know!
我发誓 我发誓
I swear, I swear it.
我去告诉其他人
I'll tell the others.
- 我是不是要把你丢在那? - 不
- Can I drop you somewhere? - No!
- 我下去了  - 好 老大
- I'm going down now. - Okay, boss.
你要专心 手不要离开方向盘
You concentrate.Keep your hands on the wheel.
是 老大
All right, boss.
好 下去了
All right. I'm coming down.
于是我的第一份工作就此结束
That ended my first career.
然后 我12岁时
Then, when I was 12 years old...
我在AP找到了一份做服务员的工作
I got a job as a boxboy at the A&P.
那是非常 非常棒的一段时光
That was a very, very exciting time for me.
我有很多 很多有趣的经历
I had many, many interesting experiences.
有一天 我在整理瓶装青菜时
One day, as I wasstacking canned vegetables...
我想那是没用的东西 不 是乳油玉米
I think it was petit pois. No, creamed corn...
或是豆煮玉米
or was it, maybe, succotash?
我不记得了
I can't quite remember.
对不起 有没有可能
Excuse me. Is there any possibility...
我自己做我自己的人质?
that I could be held hostage by myself?
我想到外面 我不怕吹风
Outside would be fine.I don't mind the breeze.
怎么了? 你不喜欢这里吗?
What's the matter?You're not enjoying yourself here?
你不必担心你的头痛了 过一会就没这痛苦了
Don't you worry your pretty little head.You'll be out of misery in no time.
等一下 你这是什么意思?
Wait a minute. What do you mean?
我老板的船在等我
My boss' boat is waiting for me.
我和他会合后 就会把这只宝贝弄沉
As soon as we meet up with him,I'm gonna sink this baby...
让你一起沉下去
with you in it.
你逃不掉的 你这下流王八
You'll never get away with this,you two - bit, fiIthy scum!
- 他叫我什么? - 王八
- What did he call me? - Scum.
也许你现在就想走 老鼠
Perhaps you'd like to leave now. Mouse.
我说的那"王八"只是
About that "fiIthy scum " comment...
住嘴 沙鱼饵
Shut up, shark bait.
- 沙鱼饵? - 住嘴
- Shark bait? - Shut up.
真是个好策略
What strategy.
你确定我们没在76年的多伦多会议上见过面吗?
Are you quite sure we didn't meetat the Toronto Convention in '76?
你真是个老疯于
You are one nutty old man.
小唐 如何了?
Sug', how's it going?
我们快到了 老大
We're getting pretty close, boss.
老大 丹西先生定会为你感到骄傲的
Boss, Mr. Dempsey should beplenty proud of you.
你把钻石拿回来了 你办到了
You got the diamonds back. You did it.
是呀!
Yeah.
我办到了
I did it.
- 丢绳子 - 知道了
- Throw the line. - Got it.
丹西先生 你的货 先生
Mr. Dempsey, your merchandise, sir.
你很不错 东尼
You're a good man, Tony.
先把事办完 然后钻石拿来 之后我们就离开
Finish your business first. Then bringthe diamonds and let's get out of here.
丹西先生
Mr. Dempsey...
我不在乎那个王八 但是那个老头子
the dork, I don't mind, but the old man....
不要留下证人
No witnesses.
- 不要再让我失望 - 是
- Don't disappoint me again. - Yes, sir.
他妈的
Shit.
对不起! 他不愿意
Sorry, Mouse, he wouldn't go for it.
对不起 我能说句话吗?
Excuse me. Could I say something?
当然
Sure.
不要杀我
Don't kill me.
我不会告发你们 都不会说 你可以信任我的
I won't tell on your gang.I won't say a word. You can trust me.
我告诉你我要如何做 我第二个杀你
I'll tell you what I'm gonna do,I'll shoot you second.
谢了
Thanks.
我要说这真是个很棒的绑架
I just want to say thatthis has been a splendid kidnapping.
谢谢 多谢你 我很感激
Thank you. Thank you very much.I really appreciate that.
我也要真心诚意的说 你是我最杰出的人质
I mean this from the bottom of my heart:You have been one outstanding hostage.
真是荣幸
My pleasure.
我说的是真的 现在我必须杀你了
No, I mean it. Now, I got to kill you.
我能理解
I understand.
并不是要针对你 我是公事公办
Nothing personal. Just business.
什么声音?
What the hell is that?
收拾他们
Take care of them.
让开 混蛋
Out of my way, dirtbag!
好 你和小唐劫持这个怕死鬼
Tony, you and Sugartake the weenie for a hostage.
我劫持这老头子 走
I got the old man. Come on!
往这里 过来 快点
This way, come on! Hurry up!
快收拾他
Get him! Take him out!
好 你们谁想拒捕?
Now, which one of you guyswas resisting arrest?
- 我不想 - 我也不要
- Not me. - Me, either.
快 塔见利 快来帮忙
Come on, Tackleberry,we need some help!
前进 高塔
Up ahead, Hightower!
稳一点 摩斯 准备跳
Keep it steady! Get ready to jump!
好
Okay, go!
- 你没事吧? - 没事
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
你去哪儿了? 怎么现在才来?
Where the hell have you been?What took you so long?
我必须换件衣服
I had to change clothes!
这可笑的衣服你从那拿来的?
Where'd you get those funny-looking clothes?
太好了
Wonderful!
所有单位在原位 等侯通知
Dispatch all units. Maintain your positionsuntil told otherwise.
往那里 稳住 到了
Over that way. Steady. You got it.
投弹
Bombs away!
我来了
Here I come! Geronimo!
- 快一点 - 我已经尽最大可能快了
- Faster! - I'm going as fast as I can!
你麻烦大了 那边没有路
You're in trouble now. It's a dead end.
小心,老头子
look out, old man!
漂亮!
Well done!
小心
look out!
爽!
All right!
他们以为他们快找到我们了
They probably think they got us!
我们快找到他们了
I think we got them!
没有出路了
There's no way out.
- 他们觉得没有出路了 - 小心 他来了
- They think there's no way out! - look out, here he comes.
- 漂亮! - 这不算什么
- Well done! - It's nothing.
快去抓他们
let's get him!
- 哈里斯队长 - 警探
- Capt. Harris. - Sergeant.
在打斗时我被锁在这里
I was locked in here during the fighting.
- 继续动作 - 是
- Carry on. - Yes, sir!
快 快点 我们把犯人绑起来关进警监
Move it. let's get these felons tied upand into police custody.
普卡特 普卡特在那里?
Proctor! Where is Proctor?
我来了! 长官
I'm coming, sir!
- 我来了 - 普卡特
- Here I come! - Proctor.
是我弄的 对不起 长官 我的错
I did that. I'm sorry, sir, my fault!
我不痛
It didn't hurt. Didn't hurt.
别在那里看笑话 拉我上去
Don't just stand there. Get me out of here!
快点 快点
Move it!
小心,鳄鱼
look out, gator!
那鳄鱼有苦头吃了
That gator better watch out.
翻 翻 高塔
Roll him over, Hightower!
不!
No!
太棒了
All right!
谢谢你
Thank you.
别乱来 老头子还在我手上
Stay where you are. I still got the old man.
- 艾里克叔叔 你还好吧? - 太好了
- Uncle Eric, are you all right? - This is awesome!
这是有史以来最棒的演习
It's the best procedure demonstrationin history!
艾里克叔叔 他们是真匪徒
Uncle Eric, those are real crooks.
那这样的话
In that case....
我不是针对你 公事公办
Nothing personal. Just business.
在这些警官抓到麦安基
After capturingthe Ma-Ankh-Ee diamond thieves...
并将之绳之以法之后
and bringing them to justice...
他们将获颂迈阿密
these officers have been citedfor medals of honor...
城市勋章
by the city of Miami.
另外 一位警官冒着生命危险
In addition, one officer selflessly...
把哈里斯队长
and at the risk of his life...
从死亡中救出
saved Captain Harris from certain death.
他就是摩西高塔警员
He is Sgt. Moses Hightower.
先让他们尝点甜头 我们才会笑到最后
let them have their little moment.We know who will have the Last Laugh.
对 我们知道 哈里斯校长
Yes, we do, Comdt. Harris.
由于他的绩效卓著
For his remarkable record...
本局决定晋升高塔干员
this department is proudto promote Sergeant Hightower...
成为高塔队长
to it. Hightower!
我想由高塔队长所救的人的手中
I think it is fitting that it. Hightower...
接下队长阶章是最合适的
receive his bars from the very officerwhose life he saved:
哈里斯队长
Capt. Harris.
你这个王八
You dork.
恭喜你 高塔队长
Congratulations, Lt. Hightower!
我很荣幸能
It has been a great, great pleasure...
担任本校的校长
serving you as commandantof this Academy.
我会想念各位的 再会
I'll miss you all. FareWell.
祝各位一帆风顺 谢谢
Godspeed, and thank you.
没有什么比我接下来要说的更让我高兴
Nothing could please me morethan what I am about to say.
州长和我希望艾里克.拉萨德
The Governor and lwish that Eric Lassard...
继续担任本校的校长
continue as commandantof this Academy...
直到他自己认为该退休为止
until such time as he sees fitto retire himself.
噢 不!
Oh, no!